非 1942年9月
North Africa, September 1942
最黑暗的时刻
A darkest hour...
全世界目睹了阿道夫希特勒的非洲军团横扫这一地区,
The world watches as Adolf Hitler high stepping Africa Corps sweeps
和意大利军队直逼埃及和苏伊士运河,
onwards to Egypt and the Suez Canal while
英军此时刚经历了惨败,
the British, our strength vdissipated by defeat
试图在阿拉曼重整旗鼓
make a desperate regroup at El Alamein.
法国战败已经两年,
Two years had passed since the fall of France.
名义上宣布中立
France now officially neutral
实际由纳粹控制
lives under Nazi domination
法国的海外殖民地阿尔及尔
and the French city of Algiers is a port of embarkation
关押着许多被法国军队抓获或逮捕的意大利,英国和德国士兵
for British, Italian and German soldiers caught
意大利逃兵已运抵
and interned by the French.
Prisoners for deportation.
前进
Forward.
上尉
Captain.
好的，中尉 ，让这些人上船吗？
Well, Leftenan... bring them aboard.
快点！
Faster.
-1个是加拿大人，其他5个是意大利人
- A Canadian, 5 Italians.
-把他们带上来
- Come quickly.
上来,快点!.
Faster, come on.
- 所都准备完毕，上尉
- All in order, Captain.
- 很好，中尉
- Very good, Lieutenant.
- 晚安
- Have a good night.
- 谢谢
- Thank you.
- 当心！
- Beware!
- 起火了！
- Fire!
快拿灭火器！
Extinguishers!
等等！
Stop!
回来或被枪杀
Back or be shot.
- 选一个
- That one.
- 加入我们，中校
- Join us, Commander.
难道你没忘了这是中立的领土
Ain't you forgetting this is neutral territory.
对不起，我们没有茶
Sorry, we have no tea.
也许你来点热巧克力
Perhaps you will settle for chocolate?
你还不肯说出自己的名字和部队吗?
Not even name, rank and serial number?
很好.
Very well.
姓名:唐纳德 克雷格
Name: Donald Craig.
军衔:少校，隶属远程沙漠集群
Rank: Major, long range desert group.
身份牌编号: 762513
Serial numbers 762513.
生于蒙特利尔
Born... Montreal.
在魁北克和伦敦学习测绘专业
Studied topography... Quebec, London.
随后到英国肯特郡矿业学校读书
Graduated work... School of Mines Kensington.
在标准石油公司工作3年
Worked three years for Standard Oil.
还要我继续说吗,少校？
Shall I continue... Major?
- 我母亲叫什么名字?
- What's my mother name?
- 伊莉萨白
- Elizabeth.
父亲：约翰・福斯特，克莱格在温哥华，退休
Father, John Foster Craig, retired and lives in Vancouver.
我明白你为什么不说话
Your reluctants to talk is understandable.
要是我不得不穿越敌军控制的沙漠,亡命300英里
If I have been force to escape across 300 miles of enemy held desert,
可到头来，
and if after all of that...
却被法国人抓住
I've been captured by French authorities,
我也肯定会很恼火
I too would be embarassed.
伯格曼上尉，你过来看，护航的飞机
Captian Bergman.
非常英国，少校
Very British of you, Major.
请不要轻举妄动,你最好先看看窗外
Before you go any further, take a look at your escort.
当然，你会确认为我们护航的是英国飞机
I'm sure you can recognised an English fighter when you see one.
你们是什么人？
Who are you?
特别工作组，特种部队
Special Identification group.
P. J. G.
The p. j. g.
- 我以为你是...
- I thought they were all...
- 德国犹太人，少校？
- Jews, Major.
是的，我们都是
Yes, we are.
德国犹太人，在英国的军队服役
German Jews serving with the British.
德国人的身份有时候很有用
However as German's, we still have our uses.
法国佬还会以为是纳粹干的
French will think this is a Nazi raid.
你应该尊重你的敌人,少校
Have more respect for the enemy, Major.
怎么,没见过飞机吗？快干活去！
What's all these? Haven't you seen a bloody airplane before?
Go away!
我是博依德中尉,信号官
Lieutenant Boyden, signals.
欢迎来到库法(利比亚)，少校这里太热了
Welcome to Kufra, Major...such as it is.
- 哈克尔上校在等您.
- Colonel Harker is expecting you.
- 希望如此，中尉
- I would hope so, Lieutenant...
是的，长官，一切都会好的
I would certainly hope so.
是的，如你所愿
Yes but of course.
来吧，上校等着呢
Come along... man. The Colonel's waiting.
哈克尔上校，长官
Colonel Harker, sir!
和伯格曼上尉到
Major Craig and Captain Bergman reporting.
上尉，很高兴你们能来
Oh... thank you, Boyden.
伯格曼上尉. 克雷格少校
Captain Bergman. Hello Craig!
很高兴你们的到来
Glad you could come.
开门见山地说吧
I'll get right to it.
克雷格，你以前曾向上面提交过一个，
Sometimes ago you submitted a plan to staff...
突袭德军在托布鲁克的油库的计划是吗？
hardlining a proposed raid on the German fuel bunkers at Tobruk.
上级通过他们无穷的智慧，驳回了我的建议
In his infinite wisdom, staff turned my plan down.
事情确实有一种改变的方式，不是吗，少校？
Things do have a way of changing, don't they... Major?
隆梅尔距苏伊士运河只有90英里
Rommel is 90 miles from Suez.
每升汽油,每颗炮弹
Every shell, every gallon of petrol he gets
要走300英里才能运到托布鲁克
has to come 300 miles from Tobruk.
皇家空军尽了力尽了职，但还是有太多补给到了隆梅尔手中
The RAF is doing its best but still too much is getting through.
所以我们要突袭隆梅尔的补给
So we're gonna have a go at Rommel source of supplies.
我是说了些什么.....
Didn't I said something to...
你觉得我的话很可笑吗？
provoke humour?
现在想到这主意的人一定是天才，
Staff has a genius for sitting on it's brain and coming
可惜结果往往与愿望背道而驰
up with perfect hindsight.
麻烦你详细解释一下好吗
Would you cared to expand on that?
我提出那建议的时候，
When I submitted the plan we could have
我们可以用百十号人炸毁那些油库
blown up their fuel bunkers with a handful of men.
现在我们要用怎么样的方法才能穿过德军的防线？
How in the hell are we supposed to get through their defences now?
乘汽车大模大样过去,少校
Drive through, Major.
我们假扮俘虏
Disguised as prisoner of war guarded by
由伯格曼上尉的人假扮北非德军负责押送
Captain Bergman personal African Corps.
我们对你的计划作了大幅修改
The plan is still basically yours
现在涉及到陆,海,空三军
but now it will be maximum effort land, sea and earth.
上校,你能给我说说路线吗？
Colonel, could you direct me to the nearest bus stop?
我们在这里，
We are here...
这是托布鲁克
Tobruk, here.
你的主要任务是
Your primarily responsibilities is to
领着我们的车队, 穿越800英里
route our convoy through 800 miles of
的撒哈拉沙漠
the west desert the Sahara has to offer
直插托布鲁克
right into the back door of Tobruk.
因此，我们费尽心思, 冒极大风险，
That's why we went to so much trouble and it was no
你知道少校
lark, you know... Major,
把你穿过大半个北非带到这儿来
to bring you halfway across North Africa.
我可没要求来这儿旅行,上校
I didn't ask for the trip, Colonel.
- 我以前来过这
- I've been here before.
- 完全正确
- Precisely.
你对这的地形的了解
Staff believed that your practical knowledge of the terrain is
是这次行动成功的关键
essential on the success of our mission.
那就是你的任务，少校
That is your job, Major.
我们现在继续，开始的时候，
Ours begin when we get there.
到达之后，我们要炸掉港口的炮台，
After we've knocked out their harbour guns installation,
引导海军登陆，炸掉油库后,
we linked up with naval assault troops, destroyed the fuel
从海上撤走
bunkers and evacuate by sea.
他们的炮台在这，梅尔沙湾
Their heavy guns are here, Mersa Cove...
- 这是自杀
- It's suicide.
- 这是命令
- It's orders.
- 我们有多少时间？
- How many days do we have?
- 八天
- Eight.
办不到
Impossible.
办不到，也得办到！
Impossible or not,
必须按计划完成它
it will be done and on schedule.
说的够清楚了吧，克雷格
Do I make myself clear, Craig?
欢迎加入,克雷格少校
Welcome aboard, Major Craig.
平时我们没有自愿者
We don't get many volunteers.
要小心犹太人,少校
Keep your eyes and ears open around the Jews,
不要太相信他们，信任太过头了可不行
little trust all right, there's no point in overdoing it.
这是我在巴勒斯坦呆了6年得到的体会
Six years in Palestine taught me that.
顺便告诉你
And for your information,
我就是提议这次行动的天才
I'm the genius with perfect hindsight.
我从来没有怀疑过，上校
Never doubted it, Colonel.
我们一小时后出发博依德中尉会为您提供协助
We leave in 1 hour, Lieutenant Boyden will see to your needs.
克莱格少校
Major Craig...
请不要因为见解不同
don't let personal differences of opinion
妨碍我们的行动
interfered with our operation.
我知道，上校
I understand, Colonel.
不过请你记住一点,就算我们到了托布鲁
I liked you to bear one thing in mind when and if we reached Tobruk,
我老妈不想让我冒险做什么英雄
my mother didn't raise any heroes.
血腥的艺术品，但我自己对自己说，画的还行
A bloody work of art, matey but I do say so meself.
是还行,只是有的地方我们还得再涂点漆
Save the Jerry the trouble of repainting if we are taken.
现在，我想的这样就完美了
Now, that's a cheery thought.
完美了
Handsome.
别偷懒了,动作快点
Come on, get cracking.
没想过得维多利亚十字奖章吗
Never get the Victoria Cross for admiring yourself.
长官，我们更可能再得到红十字
It's chai cross we're after, sir.
我只想能多感受些阳光就好了，少校
I think Dolan is a feeling a touch of the sand and sun, Major.
再罗里八嗦的话,就让你尝尝靴子的滋味
You'll be feeling a touch of my boots if you don't hop to.
这是利比亚,不是伦敦
This is Libya, not London.
妈啊，吓死我了
Well, damn bloody hell!
士兵们，全体下车
Soldiers, get off the vehicle!
列队站好，赶紧！
Line up, hurry!
注意，立正！
Attention, stand still!
中尉,整队完毕
Lieutenant, troops in formation.
喔...看到他们我怎么感到我后背凉嗖嗖的
Ooh... got a cold feeling down the back of me neck just looking at 'em.
我们要执行的到底是什么样的鬼任务,长官？
What kind of bleeding mission are we going on anyway, sir?
该你们知道的时候会告诉你们的
You know when you're supposed to and not before.
或许你自己也不知道吧？军士长
Maybe you don't know either, Sergeant Major.
好了...好了，看够了没有
All right... all right, what is this
你自己的工作都完成了吗？现在赶快
going on with the lot of you?  Come on now.
军士长
Sergeant Major!
长官
Sir!
有给我们的命令吗？
Do you have your orders regarding my men?
我们接到的命令
We'll have no dealings with you
是什么都不用做，长官！
as soldiers unless otherwise instructed, sir.
请就请让你的人严格遵守命令,中士
See to those orders are complied with, Sergeant Major.
长官
Sir!
全体,上车！
Attention, break ranks!
居然要听德国佬的命令
Taking orders from a ruddy Kraut!
这是打的什么破仗啊？
What's this bleeding war coming to?
要是我在特拉维夫的父亲
If my father in Tel Aviv could see me here now,
现在在这儿看见我跟英国人并肩作战，他肯定要替我脸红
fighting for the British, he would take back my Bar Mitzvah.
战争总是和政治奇妙的混合在一起的
War and politics, Mohnfeld. They're always mix.
他也是这么跟我说的,我得试着把它们分开
There are just the same if he ever finds out. He'll give me an a bris.
好吧，意大利人肯定和他们的德国盟友想法一样
Well, now we know how the Italians must feel with their German allies.
英国人会很快把我们投入战争
And the English will throw us to the wolves just as quick...
如果我们愿意的话
If we let them.
中士,叫大家做好准备
Get the men ready, Sergeant.
你的子弹够用吗？伙计？
You got bullets in that thing, mate?
- 就知道套近乎
- Talking to the blighty enemy.
- 我们要装扮成俘虏
- We're supposed to be prisoner...
阿法耶，根据命令,我们不能说话
...Alfie. You know the orders, no fraternizing.
我可没工夫拉关系，我只是想知道, 他的枪里有没有子弹
No fraternizing, I just asked him if he's got bullets in that chopper.
我可不想被他当猴耍着玩
I don't want him to take his play acting too much to heart.
他对我说,「这是你的机会」
An opportunity, he says.
- 谁说的?
- Who says?
- 法官.
- The judge.
3年来，你在监狱里，现在我给你个报效祖国的机会
I'm giving you the chance to serve your country
成为受人尊敬的而且有责任的公民
and to come back to society as a respectable citizen.
上帝保佑他
God bless him.
那你难道想回伦敦去，阿法耶
You wouldn't want to be back in London, Alfie...
那儿也正在挨德国人的炸弹呢
not with all them bombs the Jerry are dropping.
帮我们一个忙，他们曾经就做过
Do us a favour, all they ever did.
它总是炸医院和教堂。
It's always been hospitals and churches.
德国人绝不会去炸布理克斯顿监狱天哪,我真后悔
They couldn't hit Brixton prison in a 100 years.
天啊，这真热
God, it ain't half hot.
嘿，这就像是过山车！
Just like being on a roller coaster.
布鲁克纳
Bruckner!
- 有！
- Yes!
- 过来一下
- Come here.
敌人纵队，是坦克！
Enemy column, tanks!
是意大利人，长官
Italian's, sir.
呵，侧翼完全没有警戒
No flanking scouts.
如果我们开火,他们一点机会都没有
If we were an attack force, they'd have little chance.
他们要是开进到距离我们1000码
They should cleared us by 1000 yards.
除非他们改变行军方向
Unless they altered directions,
- 博依德中尉
- Lieutenant Boyden.
- 是，长官
- Yes, sir.
- 通知大家准备战斗
- I want every man armed and ready.
- 是，长官
- Sir!
你知道吗现在你有没有想过，布理克斯顿监狱才是个好地方
You know when you come to think of it, Brixton prison's really a nice place.
你很伤感啊,阿法耶？
You're getting soft in the konk, Alfie.
我想念那8英尺厚的砖墙,绝好的炸弹避难所
All 8 feet thick of regular bleeding bomb shelter.
那该死的法官说：「现在一切都好了」
If I could get my hands on that judge...
- 他硬要把我这无辜的人变成刽子手
- Sending innocent to the slaughter.
- 你还无辜吗？
- Innocent?
笑死我了
I will give something.
撒哈拉沙漠这么大，他们干嘛非要停在那儿?
The whole damn Sahara and they have to stop here.
- 什么事，军士长
- So, Major?
- 又有车队来了，长官
- More company, sir.
在另外一侧
Over there... on the other side.
他们肯定是德军
They must be Germans.
意大利人喜欢舒适，他们不会晚上行军
The Italians are too fond of comfort to travel this late.
他们的哨兵还没发现德国人
Their sentry hasn't seen them yet.
伯格曼,你去悄悄干掉那些哨兵
Take what man you need Bergman and make sure they don't.
布鲁克纳，跟我来
Bruckner, come with me.
他们有多远？
What do you estimate the range?
大约2000码
2.000 yards, maybe even less.
我们迫击炮射程才1000米
Twice the reached range of our mortars.
我去拿测距器
I'll get the range finder.
准备迫击炮
And prepared mortars.
准备好了吗？
You all right?
你呢？
You, okay?
好了，中尉，长官. 你不介意我问一下
Lieutenant Boyden, sir. You don't mind me asking...
那老家伙现在想干什么？
What's the old man up to now?
玩个可爱的游戏，阿法耶
A lovely scheme, Alfie.
玩个可爱的游戏
A lovely scheme.
他准备让意大利人和德国人开始自相残杀
He's going to start a bit of fighting between the Italians and the Germans.
他怎么做，长官？
How's he going to do that, sir?
首先用迫击炮先轰德国人，然后再轰意大利人
First we open fire on the Germans, then our mortars hit the Italians.
意大利和德军都以为是对方开的火，
Now the Italians see the German's column and vice-versa.
因为都以为对方是英国人
So both of them got to thinking it's the British army on the
两边互相开火，你觉得呢
other side that's doing all the firing, you see.
然后你制造了一场自相残杀的闹剧
And you got themselves a bloody battle going.
对
Right.
- 天哪。你认为我们能行吗，长官？
- Blimey, you think we'll make it sir?
- 你知道一些有用的祈祷词吗？阿法耶
- Know any good prayer, Alfie?
距离
Range?
距离800
Eight hundreds.
- 士官长...
- Sergeant Major....
- 长官
- Sir.
- 告诉博依德他们开火
- Tell Mr Boyden to open fire.
- 长官
- Sir.
先生们
Gentlemen,
是时候了，我们该走了
it's time we're moving.
真够热的,象血熔炉
It's like a bloody furnace.
高兴点，这还没到最热的时候呢
Cheer up, it could get worse.
你到底在做什么
What's the devil are you doing?
克雷格？在硬地上，我们速度更快，走沙漠要用更多的时间
We're making excellent time on the flats, why head into this area?
从我们在谷地留下的车辙，德国人很快就会明白过，上校
We leave our calling card back there in the wadi, Colonel,
德国人很快就会追踪过来
the Germans bound to find.
没错,但我们有速度优势
Exactly why speed is our best advantage.
他们也知道这一点
They know that too.
他们将会派出飞机搜索，
That's why they'll spending the major part of their times
因此我们要从这儿插过去
guarding Kalafsho Flats while we cut through here.
你知道这条路通到哪儿吗，少校？
Do you realised what you're suggesting, Major?
- 知道,长官
Yes, sir!
- 是德军的雷区！
- That's a German minefield.
- 没错
- That's right.
所以他们不会来这里找我们，他们想不到
Where they're not likely to looks for us.
我不同意,应该掉头
I don't like it. We're turning around.
那么上校，你将会
Do that Colonel and you'll
当一回真正的战俘了
reached Tobruk as a real prisoner.
It's out of the question.
哈克尔上校,你花费尽心思
Colonel Harker you went to an awful lot of trouble to
把我拐进这个行动
shanghai me in on this mission.
可既然你不听愿我的建议，干嘛还非要把我拉来？
If you're not going to follow my advise, what the hell am I doing here?
可没有探雷器,重型车辆根本过不去
You can't take heavy transport through that without mine detector.
你到底要不要听我的？你带我来就要听我的
Why are you telling me? You brought me along to tell you.
好吧,少校，我洗耳恭听
All right... Major, tell me.
谢谢你，长官
Thank you, sir.
把半履带车开过来！
Bring up the half-track.
这个季节刮南风,日复一日
This time of the year, the wind is from the south.
风把沙子长时间吹成这样的斜面
It blows for months at a time forming a
形成厚沙垫能分散压力
sand cushion at the base of the slope.
By keeping to the slope the deep sand will act as
形成厚沙垫能分散压力
a pillow dispersing our weight.
如果半履带车能过
Our heaviest pieces of half-track
其它车辆卡车也能
can make it, the others can.
我知道卡车轮胎将会陷进沙里
I know the lorries wheel will bogged down but the half-track
半履带车能控制住方向
with it's track can maneuver.
你打算如何让卡车通过？
But how do you propose to get the lorries through?
这个雷区布置有段时间了，上校
This is an old mine field, Colonel.
地雷周围堆积了很多沙子，因而会形成马鞍状
The sand covering the mines had plenty of times to settle.
只要停在斜坡上，我就能看清楚
By keeping to the slopes, I will be able to see
地雷的准确位置
the depression over the mines.
你难道想亲自去开路
So you intend to clear the way and pied piper us through?
没错
That's right.
- 泰恩军士长
- Sergeant Major Tyne!
- 长官
- Sir!
你在后面负责做好车辆的伪装
Bring a drum from the lorries with branches and camouflage
- 让大家在车上休息
- to wipe out our tracks.
- 长官
- Sir.
这可不是件容易事
It may not be so simple.
德国人总是布连环雷
The Germans often set their mines at tandem.
你碰上一个，等于碰上了一打儿的地雷
Tried to move one and you could take out a dozen.
非常可靠. 所以其余人要在我后面待着
It's very effective. That's why the rest of you will wait behind me.
在我们身后，长校
Behind us, Major.
我陪你去你不能边开车边找地雷
You can't drive and watch those depression of yours.
你愿意的话, 你就当自己是个志愿者吧
Suit yourself. You're the one who volunteer.
往左开
Go to the left.
再往左. 稳住车
Stay to the left. It's digging in.
沙子再厚点的话,我们也应付得了
Goes any deeper we're going to blow up your whole theory.
往高处走
To the high side.
停车！
Stop!
- 在这里等着
- Wait here.
- 这是我的荣幸
- My pleasure!
他还真冷静， 你认为他个种植的雏菊的
He looks so calm, you think he was planting daisies.
是啊,你要明白刺刀捅错一下
You know one wrong tickle with that bayonet
我们就要在坟墓种雏菊了
and we will be pushing up the daisies.
他想一个人挖遍撒哈拉吗?
Does he expect to dig up the whole damn Sahara on his own?
- 军士长泰恩
- Sergeant Major Tyne.
- 长官
- Sir.
叫你的人带上刺刀跟我来
Get some men with bayonets and follow me, will you?
长官
Sir.
你干嘛用手指堵着耳朵？
What have you got your fingers in your ears for?
那你干嘛不用你的爪子
What have you got your
- 堵住耳朵
- fingers in your ears for?
- 我不想站着看到血
- I can't stand the sight of blood.
你为何用手捂住自己的眼睛？
Then why don't you put your hands over your eyes?
好吧，我不想错过到底发生什么事
Well, I want to see what's going on, don't I?
- 我带的点人来了
- I've got some men coming up.
- 没必要
- That won't be necessary.
柏格曼，用机枪打第一个地雷
Give that first one a burst, Bergman.
卧倒
Down!
运气好的话我们可以打出石油
It's just our luck to strike oil.
一下个
Next one.
- 可以走了,上校
- We can move on down, Colonel.
- 我来驾驶
- Let me drive.
我们可以继续前进
We can move on then.
他们在陆军军官学校里没教过这个,长官
They didn't teach us that at Sandhurst, sir.
他们是很骄傲的,博依德
Look out the Bungalore torpedo, Boyden.
是，长官，谢谢，长官
Yes, sir. Thank you, sir.
上路,我们要按时间表前进
Get cracking, there's a schedule to keep.
还好吗？博依德
All right, Boyle?
有什么意见吗？
Any complaints?
给可可多一些糖吗,中士？
How about some more sugar for the cocoa, Sergeant Major?
你有你需要的口粮
You've had your rations that you need.
- 饭菜可口？
- Grub all right?
- 很不错
- It's wonderful.
- 有什么意见吗？
- Any complaints?
- 没有，长官
- No, sir.
- 饭菜可口？
- Grub all right?
- 不错
- Lovely.
- 胳膊怎么样?
- How's your arm?
- 哦，没事了
- Oh, fine.
- 小心点，小子
- Make good use of it, boy.
- 知道了
- All right.
长官
Sir.
- 有问题吗？
- Trouble?
- 发动机进沙，坏了
- Carburation's off.
我要说,德国人很会
I'll say one thing for the Germans,
造发动机而且还便宜
they certainly know how to build an engine.
全是免费劳工造的
It doesn't cost much, either, when they use slave labor.
200 犹太人的血汗，少校
Two hundred Jew power, Major.
我们都知道欧洲发生了什么事
We all know what's going on in Europe.
是吗？如果你知道
Well, if you do,
如果你真的知道
if you really do,
刚才就不会那么说
there must be a little of the Jew in you.
犹太人和所有人都一样
They say there's a little of the Jew in everyone.
Jah,
纳粹也是这么想的
a little of the Nazi, too.
你们的战争比我们要长,上尉
Your war's going to last a lot longer than mine, Captain.
它已经持续了2000年
It's 2000 years old now.
我们曾遍布世界各地现在
For the first time since Jesus,
我们第一次感觉是个民族
you begin to think and feel as a people.
犹太人四处流浪的日子该结束了我们要和平
Days of the wandering Jew are coming to an end.
我们要回家
We're going home.
- 回巴勒斯坦?
- Palestine?
- 以色列,少校
- Israel, Major.
以色列
Israel.
它是我们的发源地
It's where we begin.
如果英国人不给我们的土地
Anyone looking for trouble in the future,
我们会以自己取的
will know where to find us.
晚上好，少校
Good evening, Major.
Take cover!
- 隐蔽！隐蔽！
- You bleedy fool!
- 我们是英国人！
- We're British!
开火
Open fire!
- 对空火力自由射击！
- Sergeant Major Tyne.
- 长官
- Sir!
掩埋死者,照顾伤员
Formed burial party and see to the wounded.
长官
Sir!
你们四个,快过来！加快速度！
You four, over here... on the double! Come on, move!
我们埋葬好死者就走
We be moving since the burial parties is finished.
何必浪费时间掩不掩埋尸体有何区别？
Why waste the time? A few bit of sand won't make any difference.
-你没听见命令吗?
- You heard the order.
- 老远就能看见这儿的烟火
- That smoke can be seen for miles.
你看，伯格曼，有意见你跟上校说去，
Look Bergman, if you have any complaints take them to the Colonel.
要么就去找个犹太教士来
Or find yourself a rabbi.
无线电话彻底没用了,长官
It's no use, sir. It's had it.
- 应急无线电呢?
- The emergency transmitter?
- 在第三辆卡车上,也报销了
- It's dead, it was in lorry 3.
按命令,除非紧急情况,我们不得打破无线电静默，
Our orders were not to break silence except in an emergency.
开罗会以为一切都在按计划进行
Cairo will assumed we're proceeding as schedule.
下面看我们的了
Let's see that we do.
柏柏尔人
Tuareg.
停火
Hold your fire.
他肯定不是一个人
There's one there's more.
怎么搞的他们第一时间
Wouldn't be the first time
- 就想袭击车队吗?
- they attack a column.
- 英国车队
- English column.
这个车队现在属于德军
This column is currently listed as German.
克雷格
Craig.
我去看看他想干嘛
I'll find out what he wants.
中士,把衣服和帽子给我
Sergeant... your tunic and cap.
他们俘虏了两个人，他们想要换枪
They have 2 prisoners. They want guns.
该死的
Blast!
我们不答应的话恐怕会有麻烦
We've to go along. It wouldn't look right otherwise.
德军俘虏,我们正需要呢
German's prisoners.. it's all we need.
克雷格
Craig.
成交
Agreed!
掩护我
Cover me.
克鲁格
Krug.
看他们
Look at them.
我要我的枪
Wish I had me rifle.
哦,我要有相机就好了
Cor, I wish I had me camera.
不敢相信与阿拉伯人讨价还价
Trust an Arab to argue.
如果你没有兴趣，我们就要你们的头
And if you are not interested, we will take your heads.
愿平安与你同在
Peace be to you.
怎么样，这次小规模谈判结果如何？
Well, what was that little display all about?
一个筹码，上校
A bargaining point, Colonel.
他们要10支步枪和部分弹药
He'll settled for 10 rifles and some ammunitions.
俘虏？
The prisoners?
英国人
British?
一个父亲一个女儿
Father and daughter.
他们本来要交给德国人的
They wanted to be taken to the Germans.
我们必须尽快赶到开罗
It's absolutely essential we reached Cairo as quickly as possible.
否则,这场战争的进程会受到严重影响
If we don't this campaign as well as the war
itself would be vitally affected.
你告诉我，我凭什么要相信
You expect me to believe this from someone
两个沙漠中的流浪汉
found wandering in the desert?
3天之前我们在班加西
Father and I left Von Hellstern's headquarter
见过冯-赫尔姆斯泰德
in Benghazi three nights ago.
我们本该空投到开罗市郊,与当地的间谍会和
We would to be dropped outside Cairo and met by a resident agent's.
可飞机出了故障,飞行员在迫降时死了
Our plane had to make a force landing. The pilot was killed.
倒霉的飞行员落地时摔断了他的脖子
Poor chap broke his neck when we hit.
贝都因人很快就会找到我们
The Tribemen found us the following day.
Well, if you are to say who you are,
你们说自己是德国的间谍，有东西能证明吗
certainly you agent's had some means of identification.
给，有证明
There! Signed by
这是凯瑟林元帅代表元首签署的
Field Marshall Kesselring acting for the Fhrer himself.
与埃及一些军队高级官员
That paper is an agreement between the Reich and
达成的协议
a group of important Egyptian army officers.
主要内容是
For certain considerations
将帮助他们发动对不列颠的圣战
they will arise against the British in a holy war... Jihad.
这里有耶路撒冷穆夫提的签字
The signature and seal beared all the Grand Mufti of Jerusalem.
他是穆斯林世界最有权势的人物
One of the most powerful men in the Muslim's world.
一旦埃及站到我们这边
With Egypt on our side, we have
完全有理由相信整个穆斯林世界都会追随
every reasons to believe the rest of the Muslim's world would follow.
上尉，土耳其需要4
Captain, the Turks alone could put
400万军队对抗俄国
4 millions men into the war against Russia.
没错，一旦隆美尔进入开罗
Exactly, and once Rommel takes Cairo,
穆夫提倒戈，那么整个英军防御系统就会崩溃
the army of the Grand Mufti will moved against the British.
上尉先生,只要你跟班加西联系一下,
If you'll only contact Benghazi, Captain...
几小时后就会有飞机来这里来
they can have a plane here within hours.
不幸的是无线电坏了
Regrettably our radio was destroyed.
- 被英国战斗机炸毁了
- By a British fighter.
- 你必须提供一辆车
- Then you must provide a vehicle.
并即刻派人把我们护送到最近的基地
And escort us immediately to the nearest base.
你认为波曼先生是在命令一个德国军官吗？
Are you presuming Herr Portman to give orders to a German officer
- 我已经跟你解释过了
- But I explained.
- 那是你的事
- That you did.
现在...你要走就支，我们还有任务
And now, you will leave the rest to me.
我们要去托布鲁克
Our destination is Tobruk.
那是我们最近的基地
And that's our nearest base.
好好招待我们的客人,孟菲尔德
Make our guests comfortable, Mohnfeld.
当然,上尉
Of course, Captain.
孟菲尔德
Mohnfeld.
居然有德国军官叫这种古老的名字
Odd name for a German officer?
我们不是每个人都叫施密特或波特曼
We can't all be named Schmidt, Fraulein Portman.
我们早就知道埃及军队中，
We've been awared of an anti-royalist faction
有人对大英帝国不满，可想不到...
in the Egpytian military but this...
这将是我的荣誉，先生们
I'll do the honours, gentlemen.
伯格曼,你这身德国军服只是伪装
That uniform is a disguise, Bergman,
它不会装太长时间
don't carry it too far.
枪毙这个女孩都不用麻烦纳粹
Shooting the girl wouldn't trouble the Nazi's.
如果这是什么打扰你，上校
If that's what bother you, Colonel.
我只是不希望我们的军官中
What bothers me is going into action with
因冲动而鲁莽行事的人
officers who make rash and thoughtless move.
波特曼以为我们是押送俘虏的
Portman's think this is a German column
德军车队，我需要他
transporting British prisoners. I want him
就让他们继续这想法好了
to continue in that believe.
当我们抵达布鲁克，上校，又该怎么办呢？
When we reached Tobruk, Colonel, what then?
这份文件和波特曼就是我们的通行证
This paper and the Portman's guarantee our entry.
没别的了,上校
Is that all, Colonel?
不,伯格曼上尉,还有
No, Captain Bergman, that is not all.
你既然在这里服役，我希望你
While you served under me I'll expect you
像英国军官一样
to conduct youself as a British officer.
不管自己心里是怎么想的，
You'll at all times obey my orders no matter
都必须无条件服从我的命令
how disagreeable it may seem to you.
我说完了,上尉
That is all, Captain.
我能理解他的心情
I can understand his feelings.
别自以为是了,少校？
You flattered yourself, Major.
他们只对百分比感兴趣
Their only emotions are based on percentages.
死的8个人里面
Eight men were killed today.
有5个是伯格曼的人
Five of them were Bergman's.
这百分比你满意了？
How does that fit into your percentages?
克雷格
Craig!
解散
Dismissed!
想听我说句话吗？上校
May I tell you something, Colonel?
你说吧
You may.
你可真行
You're a real joy!
坐好
Come on then sit-up.
Four.
Three.
One.
晚上好，下士
Good evening, Corporal.
我想出去走走
I think I'll take a short walk.
- 晚上好，下士
- Goodnight, Corporal.
- 晚上好
- Goodnight.
明天13:00,我们进入托布鲁克
At 13:00 tomorrow we move on Tobruk.
如果我们顺利的话
If all goes well,
我们在晚上20:00拿下港口的大炮
we should be in position to take the harbour defense guns by 20:00 hours.
随后皇家空军开始大规模空袭
Our attack coincides with the massive raid by the RAF.
21:30,皇家海军会出现在港口
At 21:30, naval units will shell the harbour,
并派出部队与我们汇合
while assault troops come ashore to link with us.
我们的主要目标
Our primary objectives,
- 炸毁这儿的地下油库
- are the fuel bunkers here.
- 上校
- Colonel...
上校,如果我们无法摧毁岸防炮,我们怎么通知海军？
If we can't reached the guns, how do we warn off the navy?
这有个德国佬的无线电发射台
Jerry has a large transmitter here in the central of the city.
没有必要，希望我们用不上它
Let's hope it won't be necessary.
如果必须用，我们再哪离开？
And if it's necessary, where does that leave us?
我们不会干坐着那就采用你最初的计划，少校
We revert to your original plan, Major.
能破坏多少就破坏多少,然后...逃命
Do what damage we can to Rommel's fuel supply, make a run for it.
好吧，我不介意逃跑,可往哪儿逃呢？
Well, I don't mind running but to where?
没有海军接应,我们往哪逃？
If we're not rescue by sea, we don't get out.
少校,我们已经考虑过这种可能了
I'm aware of that possibility, Major.
在苏卢姆海滩安排了备用接应点,会有小舢板在那儿等我们
That's why we have an alternative pick-up down the coast at Sollum.
可苏卢姆海滩在德军大后方
It's a long way to go with the Germans on our back.
万一被俘,我们大不了进战俘营
If we're capture it means a POW camp.
可伯格曼他们怎么办?德国人不会留他们活口的
What about Bergman's men? They can't let themselves be taken alive.
我敢肯定,伯格曼还有他的SIG部下，在自愿参加这次行动前,
I'm quite sure that Captain Bergman and his SIG gave that
都已经仔细考虑过
a very careful consideration
这个问题了
before they volunteer.
谢谢，先生们
Thank you, gentlemen.
伯格曼！
Bergman.
我一直觉得犹太人很精明
I thought you Jews were supposed to be smart.
那是敌人的宣传，伙计
Enemy propaganda, mate.
你刚才为什么不说话?
Why in the hell you didn't speak up in there?
有用吗？
What reason?
日内瓦公约对我们犹太人无效
There's no Geneva Convention for us.
如果你只关心死亡,生命就无法留存
Begin thinking of death and you're no longer sure of your life.
- 这是希伯莱俗语
- It's a Hebrew proverb.
- 烈士也不过是具尸体
- A dead martyr's just another corpse!
到底是为什么，需要你这样的牺牲？
What in God's name drive you people.
也许是上帝的旨意
Perhaps his name is enough.
上帝...和哈克尔上校
God and Colonel Harker.
上校是个老古董，老顽固，他根本不关心
Colonel is a soldier of the old school and has old school attitudes.
我们的生死
He doesn't care much for us.
我们也不在乎他
We don't care much for him.
但我们目前需要他，他也需要我们
But he'll be there when we need him.
让我们希望他们都会没事
Let's hope they both will.
晚安，少校
Good night, Major.
别抬头
Don't turn your head.
你是谁
Who are you?
朋友
A friend.
为什么不露面
Then why hide?
听好了
Listen carefully,
我们都在赌命,但我不能暴露
my life as well as yours are at stake if we are discovered.
这只押送队不象你想的那样是德国人，波特曼先生
This column is not what you think, Herr Portman.
你是说伯格曼上尉和其它人都不是德国人？
You mean Captain Bergman and the others are not German?
犹太人...SIG
Jews... SIG.
些俘虏其实是沙漠突击队
Their prisoners are commando's.
他们的目的可想而知
Member of the long range desert group.
烟斗
Tobacco.
那个哨兵抽的烟斗
The tobacco of that sentry was smoking.
自战争开始以来，我们的军队就没有这种东西
Our troops haven't had anything to light since the beginning of the war.
- 你到底是谁?
- Who the devil are you?
- 这无关紧要
- That is not important.
你的任务才重要
Your mission is and these men know about it.
- 你给托布鲁克报个信
- You must get word to Tobruk.
- 怎么报信？
- But how?
向西走2公里
Two kilometres from here due west,
你会找到一堆石头
you'll will find a myriad of stones in the sand.
再往北走6米,沙子底下，埋着从
Buried in the sand 6 metres north of that marker is a
加亚到托布鲁克的电话线
telephone cable connecting Jalo with Tobruk.
现在
Now...
转过头去
Turn carefully...
看着
and look!
在地窖里,你会找到一部电话
In the cistern you will find the field phone.
两件披风和武器
A pair of camouflage capes and a weapon.
很好
Very well...
如果你能安排这一切,为什么不自己去找援助
If all this has been arranged, why haven't you send for help?
我不能冒险离开营地
I cannot miss leaving the camp.
只要你跟托布鲁克联系上，几小时我们的装甲部队就能到这里
Once you contact Tobruk, they can have an armour column here within hours.
如果我拒绝呢？
And if I refuse?
你还是能拿铁十字勋章
The Iron Cross will still be yours.
在你死后，波特曼先生
Posthumously, Herr Portman.
转过去,面向墙
Turn back to the wall.
30秒内不准回头
Do not move for 30 seconds.
稍息
At ease!
布鲁克那
Bruckner,
军用电话
A military phone.
英国的左轮手枪
An English revolver.
- 她开走了一辆车
- Take her to the car.
- 是的，中尉
- Yes, Lieutenant.
等等
Wait!
过来
Come forth!
快点
Come on.
- 他们怎么搞到的电话
- How did they get that telephone?
- 这非常简
- It's very simple.
我们中有只鼹鼠
One among us is the enemy.
- 中尉
- Lieutenant.
- 中士长
- Sergeant.
注意，立正！
Attention, stand still!
命令你的人交出武器
Order your men to unload their weapons.
我必须拒绝这个命令，上校
I must refused to give that order, Colonel.
泰恩军士长
Sergeant Major Tyne.
长官
Sir!
- 把他们的枪都缴了！
- Disarmed these men!
- 长官
- Sir.
你，你和你，跟我来
You, you and you, come with me.
我喜欢干这事，我从不相信这些人
That's more like it. I never did trust 'em.
德国佬就是德国佬
Once a Jerry, always a Jerry.
小偷始终是小偷，对不对，阿发耶？
Once a thief, always a thief. That right Alfie?
干正事吧
Come off it now.
到底是哪一个放跑了德国间谍呢？
Who else you think let that damn spy escape?
伯格曼上尉
Captain Bergman,
你有2小时时间找出内奸
you have 2 hours to deliver your traitor.
你最好别乱跑，解散
Try not to move, miss.
你正接受输液
There's a plasma tube in your arm.
- 帕特维特
- Britwaite...
- 军士长。
- Sergeant Major.
去叫上校来,快点
Get the Colonel. On the double!
我去找医生
I'll get the M.O!
那个信息...你们发出去没有？
The message... did you get through?
回答我
Answer me!
你把她一个人留在那了？
- You left her alone?
- 是的，长官
- Sir!
- 锁上了，长官
- It's bolted, sir!
- 撞开它
- Break it.
从里面反锁了
No one inside it seem.
军士长！
Sergeant Major!
- 长官
- Sir.
- 警戒！
- Assistance!
氰化物！快速有效
Cyanide, I've seen it often enough.
我抓住那个叛徒了，上校
You'll find your spy right down the shaft, Colonel.
是谁？
Who is it?
不知道,太黑了,看不清，少校
I don't know. It's very dark down there.
我在远处发现了秘道入口
I found the sentry at the cistern... stabbed!
他还在暗道里
But the traitor was still in the tunnel.
已经死了
He's dead!
布鲁克纳？
Bruckner.
不可能,我认识他十年了
Impossible, I have known him for 10 years.
你自己说的，那姑娘死于氰化物
You said yourself, the girl died from cyanide.
根本不是氰化物
His suicide tablet gone.
这儿，军士长，你看看这个
Here... Sergeant Major, look at this!
真是不吉利的装扮
Cor, what a mess. It's a diabolical liberty.
我相信你，阿尔菲想听我的建议吗？
You know what they say, Britwaite...
闪电不会两次劈到同一个地方
Lightning never struck in the same place twice.
那是你的幸运符
That tunic could be your lucky charm!
那个家伙肯定会流血 ，我只能告诉你这些
That guy can sure bleed, I can tell you that.
- 博依德,觉得怎样？
Well, Boyden...what do you think of that?
- 很逼真,长官
- Pretty convincing, sir.
- 谢谢
- Thank you.
- 上校,我有话要跟您说
I'd like a word with you, Colonel.
- 你们出去吧
- Excuse us please.
- 长官！
- Sir!
好了,少校,有什么话你尽管说吧
All right Major. Get it off your chest and you'll feel better.
你知道让这些人穿德军制服，
Do you realised what will happen if your men are taken in those uniforms?
万一被俘会有什么结果吗？
They'll be executed.
你一点没觉得不安吗？
And that doesn't bother you at all?
这是精心计划过且完全必要的冒险
It's a calculated and most necessary risks.
是我下命令收缴SIG的武器，
I've given orders to return ammunitions to the SIG.
我在每辆车上安排了我们英国人
I'm also assigning armed British troops
身穿德军制服拿武器掩护
in German uniform to cover each lorry.
伯格曼感觉好些了吗？
How does Bergman feel about that?
这不是一次大众比赛
This is not a popularity contest.
我一点也不在乎别人怎么看我的行为
I don't give a damn what anybody thinks of my actions,
再说他们是一群古怪的犹太人
least of all a dozen odd Jews.
没有布鲁克纳，在急要关头时
No Bruckner, when the chips are down.
你越要果断，对不对？
You passed judgement on people quickly, don't you?
你这是固执和偏见
Just like that and head's are supposed to roll.
我本来就没想过要为什么事业光荣牺牲，
Well, I 've never considered dying for a cause no matter how noble.
- 现在更加不想为你这样的人卖命。
- And I'm not about to begin now.
- 你害怕了,少校？
- Frightened, Major?
或许你血管里流的是冰水，可我血管里的血，上校
You may have ice water running through your veins, Colonel...
我一滴也不想失去它也会拒绝的
but I have blood and I need every drop of it.
我的看法，我们有两条道可以选
The way I see it, we have 2 chances of coming out of this.
- 要么善待他们，要么不
- A poor one and a slim one.
- 是的，克雷格
- Yes, Craig.
一开始,是你的热情鼓舞了我
From the beginning your boundless enthusiam has been an inspiration.
但很奇怪你会背上那么重的负担
But I'm getting rather weary of being the cross that you've to bear.
别把自己看太高了,上校
Don't flatter yourself, Colonel.
那些战士也是人
I've trunks full of crosses to bear.
你觉得好点了吗，少校
Feeling better, Major?
我们10分钟后出发
We leave in 10 minutes.
机动搜索队！
Head hunters!
野战宪兵
Field police.
没这个必要,中尉
Is that necessary, Lieutenant?
希望如此，赫尔中尉
I hope not, Herr Oberleutnant.
抱歉,这是命令
Sorry mate... orders!
对他们好些...50码远
Keep pace with them... 50 yards back.
上校,这条去托布鲁克的路上有很多岔道
Colonel, this road takes us through Tobruk and then it branches.
右边通向一座监狱,左边通向梅萨湾
To the right is the prison compound, to the left is Mersa Cove.
好的
Well...
你是军官,叫他们让开
You're an officer, clear the way.
你们！你们！闪开！
Move away!
走开，你这蠢驴
祝贺你
Congratulation!
托布鲁克的无线电发射塔就在我们后面
Their radio towers behind us.
上校,我们到了，要向总部发送信息吗？
Colonel, I think I'd like to put in for a transfer.
德军非洲军团的一半都在这儿
Half the Africa Corps.
- 沙漠之狐又有力量了
- The foxes done it again.
- 这会儿英国狮子在睡觉
- While the British lion slept.
这更证明了我们破坏德军的燃料储存任务的重要性
Gentlemen, the importance of our mission is
没有燃料，他们是动弹不得的
even graver than staff realised.
这解决不了问题，上校
That's doesn't solved the problem, Colonel.
就算我们登陆时只会遇到轻微的抵抗，
Our men are going to land expecting light opposition
可立刻就会遭遇到隆梅尔的全部预备队
and they're gonna run into Rommel's total reserve strength.
我们得占领发射塔
They must be stopped.
通知他们取消登陆行动
We've to take that transmitter.
在行动已经开始的时候向德国人发出警报
And alert Jerry, for all we know staff may have scrubbed the mission already.
- 我们什么也不做，只是等待吗？
- So, we just sit back and wait.
- 没错
- Exactly!
就算登陆行动取消, 我们也要完成自己的任务
If it has been cancel, we won't have given ourselves away.
就我们这些人怎么对付整整两个师的德国人？
What can a handful of men do against 2 full divisions?
那我们也得试一试，少校
We can try, Major.
如果这些坦克到了阿拉曼,德国人就将占领埃及
If those tanks reach El Alamein, the Germans have Egypt.
他们可能占领，但我们才是关键
They may have the lock, but we have the key.
没有燃料德国佬的坦克哪也去不了
Without fuel, Jerry goes nowhere!
你看起来不太高兴,少校
You don't look too well, Major.
一点也不奇怪
Not surprised to hear it.
我们的海军应该解释一下，
We'll have to have a word with the admiralty about this.
我还以为托布鲁克港一直被海军封锁着呢
I thought Tobruk was the name of a blockade.
也一定是有人忘了跟德国人说了
Someone forgot to tell the Germans.
那就是我们的目标
There's our objective.
隆梅尔的地下油库
Rommel's underground fuel dumps.
很显然皇家空军一直无法摧毁它
Easy to see why aircraft had such little effect.
我们已经找到了通信电缆
We've located the communications cable.
我们随时可以切断连接地堡和市区的通讯电缆
The bunker can be cut off from the city anytime.
我们去干掉那些大炮
While we go for the guns,
同时另外2组干掉地堡
two detachments will take out those pillboxes.
真准时
Right on schedule.
分秒不差
Right into a meat grinder.
- 博依德,趁空袭掩护
- Boyden, the air raid's your cover.
- 长宙
- Sir.
带上你的人去占领德国佬的发射塔
Take what men you need and go for the Jerry's transmitter.
给开罗发出取消登陆的信号，重复：取消登陆
Send an open signal to Cairo. Cancel landing, repeat... cancel landing.
还有凯塞林的文件发出去
And advise staff of the Kesselring paper.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
哈尔克上校
Colonel Harker.
中尉不会说德语,如果有人拦阻,他们死定了
If Lieutenant Boyden should be stopped, he doesn't speak German.
- 那你自愿去吗，孟菲尔德?
- Volunteering, Mohnfeld?
- 给他增加成功的机会，长官
- It would improve his chances, sir.
到防空洞。担架。清理屋子
To the air raid shelter. Stretchers. Make room.
让开！
Make way!
快来，快.....来！
Come on, move... come!
还活着
Well done.
快点，好了没有？
Harry, are you all right?
哦，是的，我很可爱
Oh yeah, I'm lovely.
我们还有事要作
Let's do it again.
起来吧，兄弟，来吧
That's more like it, my boy. Come on!
长官
Sir...
他死了
He's dead.
快点，很快就会结束的，我们逃走吧
Hurry up, it will be all over us in a minute. Lift him up.
撬开门
Pry open the door.
- 有他吗？
- Got him?
- 是的
- Yes.
快点，到这
Quick, in here!
快速找掩护
Quick. Take cover.
所有人都快点
Everyone, come on, quickly!
离开他
Leave him.
他们成功袭击的指挥部
They have succesfully hit headquarters.
担架
Stretchers.
我们真是夹在中间了
Cor, that was a whisker away.
- 现在怎么办，阿尔菲？
- What do we do now, Alfie?
- 问得好，伙计
- Good question, mate.
得好首先脱了德军制服
First of all, unload these Jerry uniforms.
我可不想被当作间谍处死
My mama didnt bring me up to be shot as a bloody spy.
亲爱的主啊！
Dear God!
什么事，你受伤了吗？
What's the matter, you hurt?
我死一定去天堂，告诉我她，看这里
I'm dead and gone to heaven, tell her. Look in there!
你看，是英国钞票,上百万英镑！
Here look, English pound notes. Millions of them!
真正的英国钞票！，阿法耶
British paymaster wrappers, Alfie.
一定是德国佬从托布鲁克抢的
The Jerries must've grabbed it when they took Tobruk from our boys.
我们可以拿回来,不是吗
Well, we better grab it back then.
等等,你弄错了,我们不是要抢钱？
Here now, wait a minute. You've got it wrong.
我们不能偷这些钱....
We weren't going to nick this money--
我们下一个，少校
We're up next, Major.
现在是21.30
It's 21:30.
博依德他们能成功吗？
Do you think Boyden got through?
我们正在被攻击！
We're under attack!
快点，你这个呆子
Quickly, to your posts!
登陆仍在，信号兵发来信号
Landing is still on, the buzzers are coming in.
- 泰恩中士
- Sergeant Tyne.
- 长官
- Sir!
带上4个人,开半履带车去公路上
Take the half-track and four men up the approach road.
用灯光示意军舰回去
Use the oil's lamp to turn those barges back.
尽你所能吧，杰克
Keep flashing as long as you can, Jack.
- 这是我们最后的机会了
- It's our last chance.
- 长官
- Sir.
- 进来，进来？
- Come in, come in?
- 怎么样了？
- What's happening?
- 线路都断了
- The line is dead.
- 继续试
- Try again.
线路接不通
It's not working.
炸药包
Satchel charge.
- 外面发生什么事了？
- What's happening here?
- 出去！
- Outside!
- 信号枪
- Flare pistol.
- 长官
- Sir.
干的不错，长官
Good try, sir.
- 看着不怎么的
- Seems to lost the old magic wand.
- 再炸一次
- Regroup now.
小胡子万岁
Heil Hitler!
- 哈尔克上校
- Colonel Harker.
- 克鲁格
- Craig.
- 我们的船来了！
- They're coming in.
- 到海滩去
- Get down to the beach!
他们需要帮助
They're gonna need all the help they can get.
掩护！
Take cover!
德国佬！
Jerries!
半履带车，开火！
Half-track! Open fire!
这些混蛋
Get the bastards.
他们退回去了
They're turning back.
- 泰恩中士他们成功了
- The Sergeant Major got through.
- 感谢上帝
- Thank God.
散开，隐蔽！
Take cover under the cliffs!
该死的坦克！
Bloody tanks!
它们会把我们炸的粉碎
They would have chopped our barges to pieces.
有那些坦克在上面，我们哪也去不了
We're just not going anywhere with those damn tanks out there.
他们把我们挡在这儿，一会步兵就会来
They've pinned us here until their infantry moves in.
上校,或许我能到上面去
I think I can get up there, Colonel.
你还是决定当烈士了
Still determined to be a martyr, aren't you?
从来没有想过，只是现在逃不掉了
I never did believe we'd get through this so long.
此外,德国人也不会留我们活口
Besides, German hospitality does not appeal to me.
你对付坦克
You pull those tanks...
我毁掉油库，作为临别礼物
and I'll give you the fuel bunkers as a going-away present.
我只是希望我的经验还有用
Best job I've had all day.
克鲁格
Krug.
我带三个人
I'll take three men.
其它就跟着克雷格少校
The rest of you stay here with Major Craig.
好运
Shalom!
好运,上尉
Shalom, Captain.
我祝你好运，伯格曼
I wish you luck, Bergman.
我诚心诚意的
I mean it.
我们都需要运气，上校
We're both going to need it, Colonel.
但不要偷我的东西
But don't steal any from mine.
我要回去了
I'm going back up!
犹太人
Mazeltov.
看
Look!
他们要来了
They're coming down!
注意，前排掩护
Watch out. Cover the rear!
好吧，各位，加快速度
All right lads, at the double!
- 我们要拿下这些坦克
- We gotta take that tank.
- 荣幸之至
- My pleasure.
不，我们用得着那坦克
No, let me have that.
需要那坦克完成任务
Need that tank operational.
刺刀
Field knife.
- 手榴弹
- Grenade!
- 快出去！
- Get out, get out!
撤退！
Dig in!
向左转,中士.闯进去！
Hard left, Sergeant! Take her through!
- 左边,88炮.
- 88 on the left.
- 中尉
- Lieutenant.
准备
Ready.
电台右上角
Hub station, off to the right.
他们陷入了混乱！
They're at an impasse.
我们先敲掉上面的，再干掉下面那个
We'll hit the top level first. Then work our way down.
我们该走了，中士，否则我们也要完蛋！
Get us out of here, Sergeant, before we blow up with it!
我的老天！
Good lord!
他们真把油库炸了
They have blown the reserve.
离不开运气....
With any luck...
隆梅尔向苏伊士的攻势到此为止了
We've seen the end of Rommel's push to the Suez.
哈尔克上校
Colonel Harker.
继续抵抗只会造成无谓的伤亡
Your continued resistance will only result in a futile loss of lives.
我要求你们投降吧
I ask you to surrender.
长官，他知道你的名字
He knows your name, sir.
和我们的情况
And our situation.
我们已经完成了预定任务
We've done what we set out to do.
举手吧
Hands up.
快走！别停下！
Come on, quick.
都别动！
Nobody move.
谁动谁死
Whoever moves, dies.
祝贺你,上校
My compliments, Colonel.
你能保证我们的伤员
I have your assurance that our wounded..
得到良好的治疗吗
...will receive prompt medical care?
绝对最好的治疗
The best we can provide.
前提是你交出凯瑟林元帅的文件
As soon as you surrender the Kesselring document, Colonel Harker.
孟费尔德
Mohnfeld.
我的名字是冯 克鲁格
The name is Von Kroeger.
冯 克鲁格
Von Kroeger,
不需要我提醒你日内瓦公约吧
need I remind you of protocol?
这是情报部门的事情
This is an intelligence matter.
布鲁克那不是内奸
And it wasn't Bruckner.
是那个犹太人在暗道里发现了我
What I told you was the truth, with one slight alteration.
，我只有杀了他灭口
That you found me in the tunnel.
文件呢
The paper please.
作为一个士兵,我们没有过多的奢望
As soldiers, we have few saving graces.
也许他该做的就是，
Perhaps our willingness to die for what we believe...
为他的信念而死
is all that matters.